<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <!-- STRINGS OF Hero CLASS -->
    <string name="Hero_Name">you</string>
    <string name="Hero_Name_Objective">you</string>
    <string name="Hero_Leave">After all the trouble of breaking in here, you\'re not about to leave empty-hooved.</string>
    <string name="Hero_ComeTooFar">You\'ve come too far on your quest to give up now!</string>
    <string name="Hero_LevelUp">level up!</string>
    <string name="Hero_NewLevel">Welcome to level %d! Now you are healthier and more focused. It\'s easier for you to hit enemies and dodge their attacks.</string>
    <string name="Hero_YouNowHave">You now have %s</string>
    <string name="Hero_SomethingElse">There is something else here</string>
    <string name="Hero_LockedChest">This chest is locked and you don\'t have matching key</string>
    <string name="Hero_LockedDoor">You don\'t have a matching key</string>
    <string name="Hero_NoticedSmth">You noticed something</string>
    <string name="Hero_Wait">...</string>
    <string name="Hero_Search">search</string>
    <string name="Hero_StaBurning">You catch fire!</string>
    <string name="Hero_StaParalysis">You are paralysed!</string>
    <string name="Hero_StaPoison">You are poisoned!</string>
    <string name="Hero_StaOoze">Caustic ooze eats at your flesh. Wash it away!</string>
    <string name="Hero_StaRoots">You can\'t move!</string>
    <string name="Hero_StaWeakness">You feel weakened!</string>
    <string name="Hero_StaBlindness">You are blinded!</string>
    <string name="Hero_StaFury">You become furious!</string>
    <string name="Hero_StaFurious">furious</string>
    <string name="Hero_StaCharm">You are charmed!</string>
    <string name="Hero_StaCripple">You are crippled!</string>
    <string name="Hero_StaBleeding">You are bleeding!</string>
    <string name="Hero_StaVertigo">Everything is spinning around you!</string>

    <!-- STRINGS OF Shopkeeper CLASS -->
    <string name="Shopkeeper_StaApply">+1 Laughter</string>
    <string name="Shopkeeper_GoneApply">You pranked the shopkeeper!</string>

    <!-- STRINGS OF HeroClass CLASS -->
    <string name="HeroClass_EarthPony">earth pony</string>
    <string name="HeroClass_Unicorn">unicorn</string>
    <string name="HeroClass_Pegasus">pegasus</string>
    <string name="HeroClass_Zebra">zebra</string>
    <string name="HeroClass_Nightwing">nightwing</string>

    <string-array name="HeroClass_EarthPonyPerks">
        <item>Earth ponies are honest, humorous, and durable, but are less kind and magical.</item>
        <item>They begin with a unique scythe that can later be reforged to upgrade another weapon.</item>
        <item>Earth ponies are accurate with melee weapons, but not as skilled with thrown weapons.</item>
        <item>They can use bows, but having neither wings nor a horn, they have a slow rate of fire.</item>
        <item>Eating a piece of food restores a small amount of health.</item>
        <item>Earth ponies automatically know potions of honesty.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="HeroClass_UnicornPerks">
        <item>Unicorns are generous and magical, but have a weak sense of humor.</item>
        <item>They begin with a unique wand of mana bolts that can later be reforged to upgrade another wand.</item>
        <item>Unicorns have a horn, which allows them to cast telekinesis at will. (TODO)</item>
        <item>The magic interference from their horn prevents unicorns from equipping a magic accessory on their mane. They can still wear one on their tail.</item>
        <item>Unicorns can fully identify a wand just by using it, and eating a piece of food will restore one charge to all wands.</item>
        <item>They automatically know scrolls of identify and cursing.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="HeroClass_PegasusPerks">
        <item>Pegasi are loyal and kind, but less generous and physically fragile.</item>
        <item>They can fly over pits, traps, and spikes. Unlike levitation, flight still triggers special plants and hidden traps. (TODO)</item>
        <item>Encumbered pegasi cannot fly well, but they can still safely glide into pits. (TODO)</item>
        <item>As long as they are unencumbered, pegasi are very fast fliers.</item>
        <item>Every time an achievement badge is validated, pegasi gain experience. (TODO)</item>
        <item>Pegasi automatically know scrolls of loyal oath and magic mapping.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="HeroClass_ZebraPerks">
        <item>Zebras are generous, magical, and durable, but less loyal.</item>
        <item>They begin with a unique throwable boomerang that can be reused and upgraded.</item>
        <item>Zebras can use thrown weapons effectively with less honesty, and get a damage bonus for excess honesty when using thrown weapons.</item>
        <item>Zebras suffer a smaller penalty than other ponies when attacking point-blank with a thrown weapon.</item>
        <item>They can use bows, but having neither wings nor a horn, they have a slow rate of fire.</item>
        <item>Zebras gain more health from dewdrops, and are immune to rooting.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="HeroClass_NightwingPerks">
        <item>Nightwings are loyal and humorous, but less honest and physically fragile.</item>
        <item>They can fly over pits, traps, and spikes. Unlike levitation, flight still triggers special plants and hidden traps. (TODO)</item>
        <item>Encumbered nightwings cannot fly well, but they can still safely glide into pits. (TODO)</item>
        <item>Nightwings are immune to blindness, and they can sense neighboring creatures even when hidden behind obstacles.</item>
        <item>They get a defense bonus for having excess honesty for their armor, or when naked.</item>
        <item>Nightwings are fast and accurate with bows, and can even fire them at point-blank range.</item>
    </string-array>

    <!-- STRINGS OF HeroSubClass CLASS -->
    <string name="HeroSubClass_NameNone">(none)</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_DescNone"></string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_NameFarmer">farmer</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_DescFarmer">The _Farmer_ can gather dewdrops and seeds from special plants, and can go longer without food.</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_NameBard">bard</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_DescBard">The _Bard_ uses laughter to recover rapidly from negative effects. This won\'t help with effects that cause damage, like being on fire. (TODO)</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_NameRoyalGuard">royal guard</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_DescRoyalGuard">A successful attack with a melee weapon allows the _Royal Guard_ to start a combo, in which every additional hit inflicts bonus damage.</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_NameMagician">magician</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_DescMagician">The _Magician_ can use her horn to cast Mana Bolts and Teleportation (which is painful), in addition to Telekinesis. Tapping monsters outside your weapon\'s range will automatically cast Mana Bolts. (TODO)</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_NameArtist">artist</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_DescArtist">The _Artist_ automatically detects cursed items, knows the ability of a ring upon wielding it, and can safely equip items with one fewer point of the necessary virtue. (TODO)</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_NamePrincess">princess</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_DescPrincess">By wearing a ring on her horn, the _Princess_ can use it as a weapon while gaining the ring\'s usual buff. Different rings produce different magical attacks. (TODO)</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_NameScout">scout</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_DescScout">The _Scout_ gains a bonus to damage when blindsiding a monster.</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_NameBeastmaster">beastmaster</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_DescBeastmaster">When the _Beastmaster_ attempts to hit an undamaged monster with a melee attack, there is a kindness-based chance the monster will become a pet. This only works with animal monsters. (TODO)</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_NameThunderbolt">thunderbolt</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_DescThunderbost">After flying unencumbered for a short distance, the _Thunderbolt_ gains a bonus to all six virtues. The bonus lasts until one turn after the flight ends. (Tweak this.) (TODO)</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_NameShaman">shaman</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_DescShaman">The _Shaman_ can brew potions more reliably, and he suffers no negative effects from eating seeds. (TODO)</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_NameSeer">seer</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_DescSeer">The _Seer_ can sense cursed items (resolve this with Artist at some point). All basic potion and scroll types are known to him. He can detect changelings on sight, which allows him to strike first. (And bonus? Tweak.) (TODO)</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_NameEnchanter">enchanter</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_DescEnchanter">Thrown weapon strikes from the _Enchanter_ have a magic-based chance of inflicting a random negative status. Additionally, weapon and barding enchantments are chosen rather than randomly assigned. (The \'evil dances\' and \'pony stew\' rumors are somewhat exaggerated, however.) (TODO)</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_NameNocturne">nocturne</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_DescNocturne">The _Nocturne_ berserks when her health is low. This temporarily lowers her kindness, but deals significantly more damage with melee strikes. (TODO fix existing)</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_NameAssassin">assassin</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_DescAssassin">The _Assassin_ has a loyalty-based chance to completely bypass monster barding whenever she fires a bow. (TODO, fix this in two places, add loyalty)</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_NameVampony">vampony</string>
    <string name="HeroSubClass_DescVampony">The _Vampony_ gains health and reduces hunger each time she defeats a monster. She also gains a boost to damage whenever she is hungry, but not starving. (weak to make cooler?) (TODO, partly)</string>
</resources>